operationxgame.com 2018-04-13

# Operation X - Privacy Policy

**Data Protection Statement of Playata GmbH and European Games Group AG**

We, Playata GmbH and European Games Group AG, are delighted about your interest in our services and in our website. The protection of your privacy is very important to us. 

The collection, processing (includes the storage, modification, transmission, blocking and deletion) und use of your data takes place in compliance with the provisions applicable under the Data Protection Act. Personal data is only collected in so far as it is technically required to provide the service. In no case will the data collected be sold or unlawfully passed on to third parties for any other reasons. 

We would like to inform you in detail about the handling of your data in this app as follows: 

**Scope of Application**

This Data Protection Statement informs users about the type, the extent and the purposes of the collection, processing and use of personal data through the responsible provider, Playata GmbH, (Vordere Sterngasse 4/6, D-90402 Nürnberg, phone: +49 911 18092338, e-mail: [mail@playata.com](mailto:mail@playata.com)) and European Games Group AG (Wiener Platz 7, 81667 München, phone: +49 89 4444 9318, e-mail: [contact@gamesgroup.eu](mailto:contact@gamesgroup.eu)). In the event that you avail yourself of services of third parties, the data protection conditions of these third parties shall apply exclusively. Playata GmbH and European Games Group AG do not verify the data protection conditions of third parties. 

**Collection, Processing and Use of Personal Data**

Personal data is information by means of which a person can be determined, that is to say indications which can be traced back to a person. These include e.g. the name, the e-mail address or the telephone number. Personal data is only collected, used and passed on by us if permitted by law or if the users give their consent to the collection of their data. 

You can visit our website without furnishing personal details. We merely store the access data without personal references such as for example the name of your Internet service provider, the page from which you visit us or the name of the file requested. This Data is evaluated exclusively for the purpose of improving our offer and allows no conclusion to be drawn about your person. 

However, if you would like to receive services in return for payment from us or take part in prize competitions or subscribe to our newsletter, personal information must be furnished. Furthermore, the automatic collection of further data such as for example the IP address is necessary for the technical implementation of our offers, the implementation of the usage relationship, the proper handling of the payment orders initiated by you as well as the monitoring of compliance with the contractual terms and the terms of use. 

As part of statistical analyses, we collect data such as the IP address and other system data in subareas of our Internet offers and apps. We use this data for statistical evaluations, particularly with a view to improving the adaptation of our Internet offers to the users' needs. In the process, the data is anonymized, if possible. 

Your data is only passed on for the handling of payments. To this effect, we transmit your payment data to the credit institute authorized to effect payment and/or the payment service provider (for example credit card companies, banks, PayPal, mobile telecommunications services) selected during the ordering process or, in the event of default, to a debt collection company or to lawyers. These service providers only have access to your personal data to the extent required for the fulfillment of their tasks. These service providers are obliged to treat your personal data in accordance with this Data Protection Statement and the relevant data protection laws. 

We use the data communicated by you exclusively for the justification, handling and execution of your order and the respective usage relationship as well as for the handling of payments without your separate consent. In addition, your data is used by us in order to communicate with you. This includes information from us by e-mail by way of our newsletter. Furthermore, we use your data in order to counteract any abuse of our offer. 

To the extent that your data is no longer required for the above mentioned purposes, including for settlement purposes, or for tax or other legal reasons, it will be deleted, unless you have expressly consented to the further use of your data. If you subscribe to our newsletter, your e-mail address will be used for own advertising purposes until you unsubscribe from our newsletter, which is possible at any time by means of the opt-out function. 

You can object to the use of the advertising ID generated by the device on your mobile device ("Opt out"). This will most probably not reduce the amount of advertising displayed, but the ads will be less based on your user behavior and probably be less interesting/relevant for you. 

_Permission for e-mail advertising (newsletter)_

By our newsletter we inform you about us and our offers. If you would like to receive the newsletter, we would require a valid e-mail address from you as well as information allowing us to verify if you are the owner of the stated e-mail address and/or if its owner agrees to receive the newsletter. Further data is not collected. This data is only used for the dispatch of the newsletter and will not be passed on to third parties. 

When you subscribe to the newsletter, we save your IP address and the date of subscription. This storage solely serves as a proof in the event that a third party abuses an e-mail address and subscribes to the receipt of the newsletter without the knowledge of the person entitled. 

You can revoke your consent to the storage of your data, e-mail address and their use for the dispatch of the newsletter at any time. The revocation can be made via a link in the newsletters themselves, in your game area and/or user account or by a message to the above-mentioned contact options. 

_Cookies_

The Internet pages use what are known as cookies in several places. They serve to make our offer more user-friendly, effective and safe. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer and saved by your browser. Cookies as such cannot be used to identify the user. The majority of the cookies used by us are known as what is referred to as "session cookies". They are automatically deleted at the end of your visit. Cookies do not harm your computer and do not contain viruses. 

Of course, you basically can use the websites and games run by us without cookies as well by setting the www browser so as to reject cookies generally or to inform you when a cookie is received so that you can decide each time whether you accept it or not. You can delete cookies that already exist on your computer from your hard disk manually at any time. However, please note that using the website and the games without cookies might only be possible to a limited extent. 

Another possibility of deactivating cookies is offered at: [ http://www.youronlinechoices.com/ ](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/)

_Access data/server log files_

We and/or our web-space providers collect data about every access to the offer (via what is referred to as server log files). This data includes the name of the called website, the file, date and time of the call, the transmitted data volume, the message confirming that the retrieval has been successful, the browser type including its version, the user's operating system, the referrer URL (the previously visited page), the IP address and the requesting provider. We only use the log data for statistical analyses for the purposes of operating, securing and optimizing the offer. However, we reserve the right to check the log files afterwards if there are specific reasons to suspect illegal use 

_Incorporation of third-party services and contents_

It is possible that contents of third parties (hereinafter referred to as "third-party" providers), such as for example videos or graphics from other websites, are incorporated in this online offer. This always presupposes that the third-party providers avail of the IP address of the user because they would be unable to send the contents to the browser of the respective user without it. Thus, the IP address is necessary for the presentation of these contents. We endeavor to use only those contents the providers of which merely avail of the IP address in order to deliver the contents. However, we have no influence if a third-party provider saves the IP address, e.g. for statistical purposes. As far as such a circumstance is known to us, we inform the users about it. 

_Use of Facebook Social Plugins_

We use social plugins ("plugins") of the facebook.com social network operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA ("Facebook"). 

Such a plugin is for example the recommendation function on Facebook, the Facebook "Share" button, the Facebook "Like" button, the Facebook "Comment box" and the Facebook "Livestream". 

The plugins can be recognized by one of the Facebook logos (white "f" on a blue tile or a "thumbs up" symbol) or are marked with the addition "Facebook Social Plugin". If a user calls a website of our offer which contains this kind of plugin, the user's browser establishes a direct connection with the servers of Facebook. The content of the plugin is transmitted directly from Facebook to your browser and integrated by it into the website. We therefore have no influence on the scope of the data collected by Facebook by means of this plugin. By the integration of the plugin, Facebook is informed that a user has called the corresponding page of the offer. If the user is logged in to Facebook, Facebook can attribute the visit to the user's Facebook account. If users interact with the plugins, for example by activating the "Like" button or by making a comment, the corresponding information is directly transmitted from your browser to Facebook and saved there. If a user is not a member of Facebook, there still is the possibility that Facebook finds out and saves the user's IP address. 

The purpose and scope of the data collection and the further processing and use of the data by Facebook as well as the associated rights and setting options for the protection of your privacy can be seen from the data privacy notes of Facebook which currently can be retrieved as follows: <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>. 

If a user is a member of Facebook and does not wish Facebook to collect data about him or her via this offer and to link this data to his or her membership data stored on Facebook, he or she must log out of Facebook prior to visiting the Internet presence. 

Please note that Facebook is constantly redeveloping its functions and applications and informs it members about data use. 

_Facebook Connect_

We offer you the possibility of logging into our service using Facebook Connect. Additional registration is therefore not possible. For login, you are redirected to the page of Facebook where you can log in with your usage data. In doing so, your Facebook profile and our service are linked. As a result of this linkage, we automatically receive information from Facebook Inc., which have been released by you in your Facebook private sphere settings (Further information at: <https://www.facebook.com/help/325807937506242/>). 

Of this data, we exclusively use the information you make available to us through these settings. This information is mandatorily required for concluding the contract as it enables us to identify you. You can revoke the permission to use this data, which you granted us, at any time via your Facebook app settings. Your account as such would not be affected by this; however, the account is linked to this information and can exclusively be used from the initially used Facebook account. 

For further information on Facebook Connect and their privacy settings, please find more information on [data policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) and [terms of use](https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms) of Facebook Inc 

_Facebook Remarketing_

This website uses the "Custom Audiences" remarketing function of Facebook Inc. ("Facebook"). This function is intended to present visitors of this website interest-related advertisements ("Facebook ads") within the framework of their visit to the Facebook social network. For this purpose, the remarketing tag of Facebook has been implemented on this website. When visiting the website, a direct connection to the Facebook services is established by means of this tag. In the process, the information that you have visited this website is transmitted to the Facebook server, and Facebook allocates this information to your personal Facebook user account. You can find more detailed information on the collection and use of the data by Facebook as well as on your associated rights and possibilities for the protection of your private sphere in the Facebook data privacy information under <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>. Alternatively, you can deactivate the "Custom Audiences" remarketing function under <https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads>.   
To do so, you have to be logged in to Facebook. 

_+1 Button of Google+_

Furthermore, we use the "+1″ button of the Google Plus social network operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States ("Google"). The button can be recognized by the character "+1″ on a white or colored background. 

If a user calls a website of this offer, which contains such a button, the browser establishes a direct connection with the servers of Google. The content of the "+1" button is transmitted by Google directly to the user's browser which integrates it into the website. Therefore, the provider has no influence on the data volume collected by Google by means of this button. According to Google, personal data is not collected if the button is not clicked. Such data, among others the IP address, is only collected and processed for logged-in members. 

Users can see the Data Privacy Policy of Google as well as information on their data protection rights and the setting options available to them for the protection of their privacy from Google's data privacy information on the "+1" button: [ http://www.google.com/intl/en/+/policy/+1button.html ](http://www.google.com/intl/en/+/policy/+1button.html)

_Twitter_

In addition, we use the [ buttons of the Twitter service ](https://twitter.com/about/resources/buttons). These buttons are offered by Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA. They can be recognized by the names "Twitter" or "Follow" combined with a stylized blue bird. By means of these buttons, it is possible to share a contribution or a page of this offer on Twitter or to follow the provider on Twitter. If a user calls a website of this Internet presence, which contains such a button, his or her browser establishes a direct connection with the servers of Twitter. The content of the Twitter buttons is transmitted directly from Twitter to the browser of the user. Therefore, the provider has no influence on the volume of the data collected by Twitter by means of this plugin and informs the user in accordance with the state of his knowledge according to which the user's IP address and the URL of the relevant website are merely transmitted when the button is downloaded, but not used for any purposes other than the presentation of the button. 

Further information on this topic can be found in the Data Privacy Statement of Twitter at <http://twitter.com/privacy>. 

_Google Analytics_

We use Google Analytics, a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses what is referred to as "cookies". These are text files which are saved on the user's computer and allow for an analysis of the use of the website by you. As a rule, the information generated by the cookie regarding the use of this website by the users is transmitted to and saved by Google on a server in the United States. 

In case of activation of the IP anonymisation on this website, however, Google will previously shorten the user's IP address within member countries of the European Union or in other contracting states of the Treaty on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address is transmitted to a server of Google in the USA and shortened there. The IP anonymisation is activated on this website. Google will use this information on our behalf in order to evaluate the use of this website by you, to compile reports on website activities and to provide further services relating to the usage of the website and the Internet usage to the website provider. 

The IP address transmitted by your browser within the scope of Google Analytics will not be associated with other data held by Google. Users can prevent the storage of the cookies by setting their browser software accordingly; however, this offer attracts the users' attention to the fact that they might not be able to make full use of all the functions of this website. 

Furthermore, users can prevent for the future that Google collects, uses and processes data generated by the cookie and related to the use of the website (including your IP address) by you by downloading and installing the browser plugin (referred to as deactivation add-on) available under the following link: [ http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en). 

As an alternative to the browser add-on or within browsers on mobile devices (e.g. tablets or smartphones) please click this link in order to prevent collection by Google Analytics on this website in future. This will result in the storage of an opt-out cookie on your device. If you delete your cookies in this browser, you must click this link again. 

_Google AdSense_

We use Google AdSense, a service for the inclusion of advertisements of Google Inc. ("Google"). Google AdSense uses what is known as "cookies", i.e. text files which are saved on the users' computers and allow the usage of the website to be analyzed. Google AdSense also uses what is referred to as web beacons (invisible graphics). Information such as the visitor traffic on the pages of our offer can be evaluated by means of these web beacons. 

The information about the use of this website (including the IP address of the users) and delivery of advertising format, which is generated by cookies and web beacons, are transmitted to and stored on a server of Google in the USA. Google may pass this information on to contractual partners of Google. However, Google will not associate your IP address with other data that have been saved of you. 

The users can prevent the installation of the cookies by setting their browser software accordingly; however, the provider attracts the users' attention to the fact that they might not be able to make full use of all the functions of this website in this case. By availing of this website, the users agree to the processing of the data collected from them by Google in the previously described manner and for the previously described purpose. 

_Doubleclick & Floodlight by Google_

Doubleclick by Google is a service by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). Doubleclick by Google uses cookies in order to present advertisements that are relevant to you. In the process, a pseudonymous identification number (ID) is allocated to your browser in order to check which advertisements were faded into your browser and which advertisements were called up. The cookies do not contain person-related information. The use of Doubleclick cookies merely enables Google and its partner websites to place advertisements on the basis of previous visits to our or to other websites on the internet. Google transmits the information generated by the cookies to a server in the USA where it is stored. Google observes the data protection provisions of the US Safe Harbor Agreement and is registered with the Safe Harbor Program of the US Department of Commerce. Google transmits the data to third parties only on the basis of statutory provisions or within the scope of order data processing. In no case will Google link up your data with other data collected by Google. 

By using our websites you agree to the processing of the data that Google has collected about you and to the type of data processing described above and to the mentioned purpose. You can prevent the storage of the cookies by setting your browser software accordingly; however, we attract your attention to the fact that in such case you might not be able to make full use of all the functions of our websites. Furthermore, you can prevent Google from collecting and processing the data generated by the cookies and related to your use of the websites by downloading and installing the browser plugin available under the following [link](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous?hl=en) under the item DoubleClick-Deaktivierungserweiterung (DoubleClick deactivation extension). Alternatively, you can deactivate the Doubleclick cookies on the page of Digital Advertising Alliance under the following [link](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). 

_Admob_

We are using the advertising partner AdMob Google Inc. for the insertion of advertising spots into the app. Here, the privacy statement of AdMob is applicable, which you can find under the Internet address <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>. For managing the advertisements we are using the so-called "Google Werbe ID" and/or the Apple "Advertising Identifier" in order to be able to display suitable advertisements for you. The use of these IDs does not enable us to draw any conclusions on your person. 

_Adscale_

Adscale uses anonymized data in order to control the display and delivery of advertising materials. This type of data is primarily cookies, numeric IDs or time stamps. This data does not contain any references to persons and is not used to establish such references. Moreover, all information has an expiry date after which it is automatically deleted. In the majority of the cases, this takes place within a few days. Adscale uses this information for technologies that are customary in the market, such as e.g. frequency capping, click tracking, conversion tracking and targeting, in order to improve advertising on the internet for the user. 

If you do not wish to receive any usage-based advertisements from Adscale and/or its service providers in the future, you can deactivate the collection of data with the respective supplier by clicking on the link below. Deactivation must be carried out separately for each individual supplier. Please note that the deactivation of data collection through cookies does not mean that you will no longer receive advertisements in the future but merely that the delivery of advertisements by Adscale and the suppliers mentioned below will no longer take place on the basis of anonymously collected user data. 

Opt-out adscale cookie: [click here to unsubscribe](http://ih.adscale.de/adscale-ih/oo). (Note: You will receive no confirmation; a simple click suffices for unsubscribing.) 

_Adjust_

This website/app also uses, among other things, the "adjust.io" analysis technology of adjust GmbH, Saarbrücker Str. 38a, 10405 Berlin ("adjust"). Adjust uses abridged or anonymized device and/or connection information. The information collected through usage merely serves to analyze the function and the use of the app by creating anonymized evaluations and charts on the number of visits, the number of pages called per user etc. The analyses are exclusively used for own market research purposes as well as for the optimization and needs-based design of the app. Data collection and storage can be contradicted at any time with effect for the future by e-mail to [optout@adjust.io](mailto:optout@adjust.io). 

_Amazon_

We are participants in the partner program of Amazon EU, which has been designed to provide a medium for websites by means of which advertising cost reimbursement can be earned by the placement of ads and links to Amazon.de. Amazon uses cookies in order to be able to trace the origin of the orders. Among other things, Amazon can see that you have clicked the partner link on this website. Further information on data use by Amazon can be seen from the [ Company's Privacy Statement. ](https://www.amazon.de/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=3312401)

_Criteo_

This website is using the Criteo service of Criteo SA, Rue Blanche, 75009 Paris, France (<http://www.criteo.com/>). By means of this service, users who have already visited our website once and were interested in our offers are offered specific advertisements on this website and on Internet pages which equally use the Criteo Service. The insertion of these ads takes place on the basis of information about the visits to the respective Internet pages, which is saved in cookies, among other things, on the user's computer. Within the framework of subsequent visits to the website, these text files are selected for specific product recommendations. For this purpose, a randomly generated identification number is saved in the cookies. In this context, neither this number nor the information on your visits to the Internet pages can be allocated to you personally. In no case can the data be used to identify you personally as a visitor of our websites. 

You can prevent this information from being saved and used by the Criteo service by clicking the following link (<http://www.criteo.com/privacy/>) and by setting the slider there from "Opt-Out" to "On". By selecting "ON", a new cookie (opt-out cookie) is set in your browser. This cookie signalizes to the service of Criteo that Criteo is no longer allowed to collect and process data about your usage behavior. You have the possibility of reactivating this function by putting the slider to "OFF". Please note that this setting must be carried out for every browser used by you. If all the cookies in your browser are deleted, the opt-out cookie will be deleted as well. 

_Lifestreet Media_

Within this service, information on the surfing behavior of the website visitors is collected and saved in anonymized form for marketing purposes using the technology of LifeStreet Corporation, 981 Industrial Road, Suite F, San Carlos, CA 94070, USA. This data is saved on the users' computers by means of so-called "cookie" text files. LifeStreet analyzes the surfing behavior by means of an algorithm and can subsequently display specific product recommendations as personalized advertising banners on other websites (so-called publishers). In no case can this data be used to identify the visitor of this service personally. The collected data is merely used for the improvement of the service. The data is not used in any other way and is not transmitted to third parties. 

You can find more information on the technology of LifeStreet on the data privacy page of LifeStreet: <http://www.lifestreetmedia.com/privacy/>. Here, you can object to data collection by Lifestreet: [ http://www.lifestreetmedia.com/optout/ ](http://www.lifestreetmedia.com/optout/)

_Simplaex_

This tool enables us to trace the actions of users after they have been redirected to a website of the provider by a click on the advertisement of a partner. In this way, we can record the effectiveness of Facebook or Twitter or Google advertisements for statistical purposes or for market research purposes. The data collected in the process are anonymous. This means that we do not see any personal data of individual users. However, the collected data of Facebook or Twitter or Google is saved and processed. We will inform you about this according to the information available to us at the relevant point in time. Facebook, Twitter and Google can combine this data with their Facebook-, Google- or Twitter Account and use it in accordance with their own privacy policy under: 

or 

for their own advertising purposes. 

Opt-Out for Simpleax: [ https://tracker.simplaex.net/v1/opt-out ](https://tracker.simplaex.net/v1/opt-out)

_SpotXChange_

Our website uses SpotXChange, a service of SpotX Deutschland GmbH, Strassenbahnring 18,   
20251 Hamburg, Germany. Among other things, SpotXChange uses cookies which are saved on your computer and allow for an analysis of the use of the website. Within the framework of the website use, data such as the IP address and activities of the users, in particular, can be transmitted to a server of SpotX Deutschland GmbH and be saved there. SpotXDeutschland GmbH will transmit this information to third parties, as appropriate, if this is prescribed by the law, or to the extent that this data is processed by third parties. You can prevent that this personal data (particularly your IP address) is collected, forwarded and processed by deactivating the execution of the Java script in your browser or by installing a tool like 'NoScript'. You can retrieve further information on data protection in connection with the use of SpotXChange under the following link: [ http://www.spotxchange.com/privacypolicy/](https://www.spotxchange.com/privacy-policy/). 

_Ströer Digital Media_

Additional targeting cookies can be set via our marketing partners, Ströer Digital Media GmbH and TRAVEL AUDIENCE GmbH. In order to avail yourself of your associated right of objection against targeting cookies in a generally valid way - not only for our portal - please consult the data protection notice of Ströer Digital Media GmbH under [ http://www.stroeerdigitalmedia.de/datenschutz ](http://www.stroeerdigitalmedia.de/datenschutz) and/or their Privacy Policy. 

Further information on usage-based online advertising is also available in the consumer portal [http://www.meine-cookies.org](http://www.meine-cookies.org/). In addition, you can deactivate or activate the collection of usage data with other suppliers and view the status of activation with different suppliers on meine-cookies.org by clicking on the following link: <http://www.meine-cookies.org/cookies_verwalten/praeferenzmanager-beta.html>. 

**Please note:** Your objection is saved on your computer by means of cookies. The cookies only contain the information that you have objected to the use of your data within the framework of tracking and/or online targeting. Without these cookies it is not possible to see and observe your objection. In order to ensure that the objection is durably activated, you should not delete the cookies on your computer manually. If you delete your cookies, the objection must be made again in the above-mentioned way. In addition, the objection must be made for each individual computer and browser used by you. 

**No Liability regarding Compliance with Data Protection by Partners**

On our pages we refer to different cooperation partners (hereinafter: "third-party providers") who in turn attract attention to online services and offers. These third-party providers regularly have own data protection provisions. Please inform yourself independently with regard to these provisions as Playata GmbH and European Games Group AG cannot assume any liability in this respect. 

**Data Security**

We process the information collected from you in accordance with the German Data Protection Act. All employees are obliged to comply with data secrecy and the data protection provisions and have been instructed accordingly. 

**Right of Information and Revocation of Consent**

According to the Federal Data Protection Act, you are entitled to cost-free information about your personal data saved with us and, if applicable, to the correction, locking or deletion of this data. 

To the extent that the processing of your personal data refers to a consent given by you and not on contractual or legal bases, you are free to revoke your consent to data processing for the future. 

To the extent that your revocation refers to the receipt of newsletters or other e-mails, we will attract your attention to the possibility of unsubscribing from such newsletters or e-mails in every topical information we send you. Costs other than transmission costs in accordance with the basic rates (i.e. the costs of your Internet, e-mail, mobile phone or telephone connection) are not incurred for unsubscribing from newsletter or e-mail delivery. Furthermore, please contact the support service of the relevant website and/or game used by you for the revocation of your declarations of consent. Please let us know the online game used by you and your player name, if possible. 

**Service Responsible for Data Protection**

If you have any questions regarding the collection or processing or use of your personal data, information, the correction or locking or deletion of data, or the revocation of declarations of consent, please contact us: 

European Games Group AG, Wiener Platz 7, 81677 München, Data Protection Officer: Maximilian Hartung (eDSB of Datenschutz Agentur), e-mail: [privacy@gamesgroup.eu](mailto:privacy@gamesgroup.eu)

**Updates**

We update this Data Protection Statement regularly and reserve the right to make changes to it. Therefore please regularly check whether a new version is available. The date of the last change of this document is shown at the bottom of this page. 

_Last updated: March 2017_
